Hey everybody, welcome to this A2
English listening practice video. I hope
you're doing well. In today's listening
practice video,
I'm going to talk about speaking styles.
And in my last video,
in which I talked at normal speed, I
talked a lot about my personal speaking
style and why it might be easier for you
to understand me even when I speak at
normal speed compared to other native
speakers. So,
this is an interesting topic because
everyone has their own speaking style
and some people are easier to understand
than others. And so,
I think that this is something that's
relevant for you especially as an
English learner because some people will
be harder to understand than other
people. By the way, excuse the
sunglasses and the sun in my face.
It's getting colder here and I kind of
want to be in the sun. So, I know I look
a little funny but I'm sure you don't
mind. So, let's talk about this and
before we do that, remember that if you
want my advanced episodes in which I
speak at normal speed, then click on the
link down below to sign up for those.
Okay, so everybody has their own
individual speaking style and it makes
them either easier or harder to
understand. And that will also depend on
you, the listener. Some people will be
easier for you to understand and some
people will be easier for another
English learner to understand.
It depends but everyone has their own
speaking style. And this is why you
might feel good about your comprehension
one day
and then the next day you feel terrible
about your listening skills because
maybe the first day you
listened to someone who is
easier to understand because of their
speaking style and then the next day you
listened to someone who has a harder
speaking style.
This has happened to me many times where
one day I feel great about my listening
skills,
maybe in French, and then the next day
it's like
man, what happened? I thought I had a
good level of comprehension and I feel
that way because I listened to content
in which the person had a harder style
of speaking, right? So,
this is also why it can be hard to
really gauge or measure your level. It
can be hard to determine your level of
comprehension
because
you might understand some content really
well and then other content you can't
understand well. So, it's hard to really
gauge your overall level of
comprehension.
For me too, when I think of languages
I've learned,
it's hard for me to say exactly how good
my comprehension is because depending on
the situation,
I might understand everything or there
might be a lot of stuff I don't
understand and this is largely because
of the person's speaking style. So,
it can be hard to gauge your level and
the goal in general is to just
understand people in general, right? We
want to just feel like we can understand
people in whatever context we're in.
That's a great goal to have. I think we
would all agree that this is the level
of comprehension that we're looking for
where we can just understand the
language, right? And so,
that means that we need to be able to
understand a variety of speaking styles
because sometimes a speaking style is
going to be harder to understand and if
we want to function well in that
language, we also need to understand
that harder speaking style
fairly well, right? And this is why it's
good to use a variety of content when
you're listening in a foreign language.
I know a lot of you probably use a bunch
of my content and you're
probably going through the playlists of
the A1 videos, the A2 videos or whatever
and you just
really like this content because you can
understand me.
And that's great but of course, just
because you understand me doesn't mean
that you can understand other native
speakers. And so, that's why it's great
to use a variety of content, not just
mine. As much as I love the fact that
you like my content, you use my content,
you need to use a variety of content if
you want to understand different
speaking styles. I have a very
particular way of speaking that is
different from other people. So,
the
the way that you can just improve your
overall understanding of people
regardless of their speaking style is of
course number one to use different
variety a different variety of content
of course like I just mentioned. But
number two, you just want to know and
understand more words and phrases. The
more words and phrases that you know and
you can understand, the easier it will
be to understand people of different
styles because of course, people that
speak
with different styles of speaking, they
use different words. They use different
phrases, different slang, different
idioms, different expressions. And so,
the more phrases and the more words you
know, the more likely you will be
to understand different people and the
less you'll struggle because a big part
of our speaking style is the vocabulary
we use. The words and phrases I use are
somewhat different from the words and
phrases that my friends use for example
and we tend to kind of use the same
words and phrases again and again. So,
if you're only using my content, you're
only learning the words and phrases that
I use. So, in general, the more words
and phrases you know, the more people
you will be able to understand.
But of course, even if you learn many
words and phrases,
there will still be people who are
harder to understand than other people
because
it's not only about words and phrases.
It's about our pronunciation, our
accent,
the way that we speak. There are other
things involved in
this question of a person's speaking
style. So, don't be discouraged even
though you have trouble understanding
people
even though you know a lot of words and
phrases. This will just take time as you
spend more time with a variety of
content, okay? So,
you won't just suddenly be able to
understand everyone even if you have a
great
knowledge of vocabulary and grammar and
slang and all of that.
There's more to it and English in
particular is a hard language to
understand. I say that because
there's
more complexity with our sound and
stress system in English. So, it's a
harder language to understand than other
languages
that might be phonetic meaning
one letter represents one sound and you
know exactly how every word sounds.
English is not at all like that. So,
it's
harder to understand. It's very common
to understand something when it's
written down but then you hear that same
sentence without seeing the words and
suddenly you can't understand it.
English is like that and it's going to
take time to get accustomed to that,
okay?
And then now, let me talk about my style
of speaking. So,
I speak relatively clearly and I don't
speak very fast even when I'm speaking
at normal speed. And I don't mumble a
lot. Mumbling is when people kind of
talk like this blah blah blah and they
don't open their mouth a lot. I don't do
that. I I have the opposite problem. I
open my mouth a lot and I accidentally
spit because of how
much I enunciate, how clearly I say
words. So, I have the opposite issue and
I have always talked in a clearer way
than other people even before I was an
English teacher. So, this isn't just
because I make content for English
learners. I've always been a
storyteller. I've always loved telling
stories,
recounting things like telling people
about things that have happened. I've
always been kind of a storyteller.
So, I've always had
this style of dramatic speaking and
using my hands and spitting,
>> [laughter]
>> things like that. And I've always been
focused on communication. This is my
main skill.
I have very few technical skills
unfortunately. But I have one skill
which is communication in general. I'm
not saying I'm the best speaker or
communicator, not at all. But what I
mean is that I'm very focused on the
details of communication and I notice
things that other people might not
notice and I can usually communicate in
a way that is appropriate for my
listener. That's kind of my main skill,
let's say, and it helps me do what I do.
So, I'm thankful that God gave me that
that skill.
And this is why
my advanced content, like my advanced
episodes, for example, are helpful for
people that are trying to start
to use like native level content, but
it's just a little too hard for them.
Usually my advanced episodes are like
the bridge between that because I'm
easier to understand than other native
speakers.
So, even when I speak at normal speed,
it's usually easier to understand than
other native speakers. And of course, I
provide the transcript. This is guided
content. So, if that's you, if you're
looking for content that's harder than
this video right now, you need to start
to use native level content, but it's
probably helpful to use my guided
content which will be like an
intermediate step between this and
native level content where just some
random person is speaking. So,
my advanced content, my advanced
podcasts
episodes are good for that.
And then
you can also use my US Conversations
Podcast. I know I talk a lot about these
things, but it's cuz people ask me over
and over in the comment section like B1
videos, B2 videos, please, C1 videos.
And I keep saying this, you know, that
there's this advan- advanced content.
And I talked about this in the last
video. If you're looking for B1, B2, C1
level content, you should try to use
guided native level content. This is
really going to help your listening.
It's going to help you take your
listening to the next level. So,
my US Conversations Podcast is great for
this as well because I talk to different
people with different styles of
speaking. So, you get the chance to hear
different styles, different varieties.
So, it's challenging, of course, but the
good thing is I'm part of the
conversation. It's me and another person
in each episode. So, it's easier than
just other conversations between two
random people
because you understand me better than
other people. So,
because I'm part of these conversations,
it makes them easier to understand. And
of course, I provide the transcript with
the definitions of key words and phrases
we use. So,
if you're looking for
content that is harder than this, you're
wanting the B2 stuff or whatever, just
know that what you're looking for is
authentic native content, but that's
guided probably. And even better,
if you understand me well, then you can
use content in which I'm a part of. So,
that can help with that. So,
if this video is just too easy for you,
you didn't even need to read the
subtitles, then you should be using my
harder content. Okay? The next level is
my advanced content, my advanced podcast
or my US Conversations Podcast. And so,
those links are down below. Please check
those out and just know that if you ask
me for B1, B2, C1 content, my response
is basically what I said in this video
and in the last video, use my guided
authentic advanced content. It's me
speaking at normal speed either by
myself or with another person, but it's
guided with a transcript and it's easier
than just other native level content.
Okay. I know I talked a lot in this
video and in the last one about, you
know, my content and this stuff, but
hopefully this answers your questions
about, you know, B1 content, B2 content,
C1 content. Hopefully
you understand now
my response to those questions. Okay.
So, check out those
those resources, my advanced podcast and
my US Conversations Podcast by clicking
on the links down below. All right.
Thank you all for watching this video
and I'll talk to you in the next one.